<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cluster Optimizer – Releases</title>
    <link>/blog/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Releases on Cluster Optimizer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/blog/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer version 1.2.1 has been released</title>
      <link>/blog/2024/05/30/cluster-optimizer-version-1.2.1-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024/05/30/cluster-optimizer-version-1.2.1-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; version 1.2.1 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database Schema is automatically upgraded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support testing notification channel connectivity to facilitate verification of the correctness of input parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer version 1.2.0 has been released</title>
      <link>/blog/2024/05/20/cluster-optimizer-version-1.2.0-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024/05/20/cluster-optimizer-version-1.2.0-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; version 1.2.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication and authorization: Supports user authentication and permissions, providing users with two roles: &lt;strong&gt;Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;User&lt;/strong&gt;. Administrators have all operation permissions, and users only have viewing permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster access account: Supports management of user&amp;rsquo;s cluster access account, and can set a cluster-level cluster access account for each user, including the user&amp;rsquo;s cloud service provider account, and the cluster&amp;rsquo;s Kubeconfig and other configurations. Users can operate the corresponding cluster through this identity. At the same time, if the cluster supports automatic Kubeconfig update, the user&amp;rsquo;s cluster access account can also be updated regularly when in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated actions: Support application-level resource recommendation, unset resource quotas and memory overflows, and delete unused persistent volumes and other automated actions. Support standard workloads &lt;em&gt;Deployment&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;StatefulSet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;DaemonSet&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CronJob&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; is not supported, and its resource quota (Resource Quota) cannot be modified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Task management: Supports daily task management operations such as creating, running, re-running, canceling, viewing task logs, and deleting tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer version 1.1.0 has been released</title>
      <link>/blog/2024/04/09/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024/04/09/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; version 1.1.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Cloud EKS integration: Supports importing AWS EKS clusters and viewing optimization suggestions for the clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU node: Supports viewing GPU nodes with low GPU utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick resource association: Supports quick association of resources with corresponding departments, groups, and users through resource tags, and can be displayed on the Web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email notification: For specific optimization strategies, users can subscribe to email notifications to learn about corresponding optimization suggestions through email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster status: Can display the status of Kubernetes and Metrics services imported into the cluster. For abnormal conditions, the cause of the abnormality can be quickly discovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support automatic creation of database Schema: You can use the parameter &lt;code&gt;createDatabaseIfNotExist&lt;/code&gt;=&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; in the database connection configuration item to indicate whether to automatically create the database if the database does not exist. When the specified user name and password have permission to create a database, the system will automatically create the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer version 1.1.0 has been released</title>
      <link>/blog/2024/01/08/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-has-been-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2024/01/08/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-has-been-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; version 1.0.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alibaba Cloud ACK integration: Supports importing Alibaba Cloud ACK clusters and viewing optimization suggestions for the cluster, including node groups, nodes, disks, persistent volumes, and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings: support create, edit and delete clusters and cloud provider&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
