<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiseinf – Cluster Scaling</title>
    <link>/tags/cluster-scaling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cluster Scaling on Wiseinf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/cluster-scaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Ruyi: A Cloud-Native Cluster Scaling Engine</title>
      <link>/docs/ruyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/ruyi/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruyi provides an automated and intelligent cloud-native cluster scaling engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruyi offers an automated and intelligent cloud-native cluster scaling engine, with main features including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-scaling: Provides auto-scaling based on Pod Requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual Capacity: Employs automated and intelligent technology to elastically scale node capacity, supporting the scheduling of as many Pods as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-cloud Support: Supports AWS, Alibaba Cloud, with more cloud service providers being integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring and Management: Offers multi-dimensional monitoring metrics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can call up the search engine &lt;code&gt;ifly_search&lt;/code&gt; using the `&amp;mdash;
categories: [&amp;ldquo;Cluster Scaling&amp;rdquo;]
tags: [&amp;ldquo;Ruyi&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Cluster Scaling&amp;rdquo;]
title: &amp;ldquo;Ruyi: A Cloud-Native Cluster Scaling Engine&amp;rdquo;
linkTitle: &amp;ldquo;Ruyi: A Cloud-Native Cluster Scaling Engine&amp;rdquo;
weight: 2
description: &amp;gt;
Ruyi: A Cloud-Native Cluster Scaling Engine.
resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;src: &amp;ldquo;**.{png,jpg}&amp;rdquo;
title: &amp;ldquo;Image #:counter&amp;rdquo;
params:
byline: &amp;ldquo;Wiseinf Inc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruyi offers an automated and intelligent cloud-native cluster scaling engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruyi provides an automated and intelligent cloud-native cluster scaling engine, with key features including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto-scaling: Offers auto-scaling based on Pod Requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtual Capacity: Elastically scales node capacity using automated and intelligent technology, supporting the scheduling of as many Pods as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-cloud Support: Supports AWS, AliCloud, with more cloud service providers being integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring and Management: Provides multi-dimensional monitoring metrics data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this document, we will introduce Ruyi&amp;rsquo;s main functions and usage scenarios in detail, and provide you with a detailed guide to help you use Ruyi more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
