<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cluster Optimizer – Cluster Optimizer</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cluster Optimizer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Evaluate cluster hibernation cost savings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/09/11/evaluate-cluster-hibernation-cost-savings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/09/11/evaluate-cluster-hibernation-cost-savings/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-hibernation-overview&#34;&gt;Cluster Hibernation Overview&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#cluster-hibernation-overview&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major challenges when using cloud-native clusters is resource underutilization, which leads to unnecessary costs. For instance, offline clusters such as development, testing, or demo environments often experience low utilization outside of working hours, yet organizations still pay for these idle resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Hibernation&lt;/strong&gt; provides a mechanism to automatically or manually manage the suspension and resumption of clusters. By releasing and restoring nodes, it reduces resource consumption and optimizes resource utilization, ultimately leading to cost savings. For example, by configuring a hibernation strategy that shuts down clusters during off-hours (e.g., nights or weekends), companies can significantly reduce unnecessary resource usage and, consequently, operating costs. This makes Cluster Hibernation an effective cost management strategy, especially for non-production environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-hibernation-strategies&#34;&gt;Cluster Hibernation Strategies&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#cluster-hibernation-strategies&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Hibernation&lt;/strong&gt; works by gradually releasing nodes during the hibernation period while preserving the state of workloads (e.g., Deployments, Jobs) in the cluster. Upon resumption, the cluster nodes and workloads are restored to their pre-hibernation state. Clusters are typically managed through node groups (also known as node pools), which can consist of different node types such as reserved nodes (e.g., subscription-based) and on-demand nodes (e.g., pay-as-you-go or spot instances). Depending on whether a node group supports autoscaling, different hibernation strategies can be applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-autoscaling-node-groups&#34;&gt;Non-Autoscaling Node Groups&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#non-autoscaling-node-groups&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-autoscaling node groups, where the number of nodes is fixed and does not dynamically adjust to workload demand, node management must be performed manually. During hibernation, the node count is set to zero, prompting the cloud provider to gradually release the nodes in the group. Upon resumption, the node count is restored to its original value. It is important to note that setting the node count to zero does not necessarily mean all nodes will be released. Reserved nodes, for instance, are typically retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;autoscaling-node-groups&#34;&gt;Autoscaling Node Groups&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#autoscaling-node-groups&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoscaling node groups dynamically adjust the number of nodes based on actual workloads, optimizing resource usage. For such groups, the hibernation strategy involves modifying adjustable workloads and relying on the autoscaling strategy to downscale the nodes. For example, setting Deployment replicas to zero or pausing CronJobs triggers the autoscaling mechanism to reduce the number of active nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cluster-hibernation-benefit-evaluation&#34;&gt;Cluster Hibernation Benefit Evaluation&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#cluster-hibernation-benefit-evaluation&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hibernation-savings-estimation-tool&#34;&gt;Hibernation Savings Estimation Tool&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#hibernation-savings-estimation-tool&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide the &lt;code&gt;cluster-hibernate-saving-estimate&lt;/code&gt; tool to help users assess potential resource savings within a cluster. This tool scans each node group within the cluster and provides an overview, including the maximum potential savings, current savings, recommended actions, and the total sum of resource requests from Deployments in the node group. Key metrics include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max Potential Saving&lt;/strong&gt;: The maximum savings achievable by optimizing the node distribution (e.g., adjusting node types to an ideal setup).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Saving&lt;/strong&gt;: The savings attainable under the current configuration of the node group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sum of Deployment Resource Requests&lt;/strong&gt;: The total resource requests (CPU, memory) of Pods in the group’s Deployments, serving as a reference for evaluating resource usage. Higher request totals typically indicate greater potential savings in autoscaling node groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hibernation Savings Estimation Tool can be downloaded from &lt;code&gt;https://github.com/wiseinf/cluster-hibernate-saving-estimate/tags&lt;/code&gt;. It currently supports platforms like Alibaba Cloud and AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore two common scenarios to evaluate the benefits of Cluster Hibernation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scenario-1-non-autoscaling-node-group-with-reserved-nodes&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: Non-Autoscaling Node Group with Reserved Nodes&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#scenario-1-non-autoscaling-node-group-with-reserved-nodes&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In non-autoscaling node groups containing only reserved nodes, a typical output is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NodeGroup: cpu-ng(npa324882932487c9777eaa7f6854e4)  Total Nodes: 4  Autoscaling: false
  OnDemandNodes: 0  
  SpotNodes: 0  
  ReservedNodes: 4  cpu: 32 cores, memory: 128 gib
    Node: cn-beijing.171.19.105.70(i-bp19u4ufadv9niflo1o4) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.g7ne.2xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
    Node: cn-beijing.171.19.105.74(i-bp19u4ufadv9niflo1o3) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.g7ne.2xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
    Node: cn-beijing.171.19.105.71(i-bp19u4ufadv9niflo1o5) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.g7ne.2xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
    Node: cn-beijing.171.19.105.251(i-bp161b0ldoqt1k771t5e) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.g7ne.2xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
  Max Potential Saving: CPU: 14125.71 core hours; Memory: 56502.86 gib hours
  Potential Saving: No saving, no spot or on demand nodes
  Recommendation: adjust some reserved nodes to on-demand or spot nodes based on its usage
  Sum of Deployment Resource Requests: CPU 8.63 cores, Memory 18.68 gibs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This node group consists of four reserved nodes, with a total of 32 CPU cores and 128 GiB of memory. Assuming the node group hibernates every evening (9 PM) and resumes in the morning (8 AM) from Monday to Friday, the potential savings are calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maximum CPU savings: &lt;strong&gt;14,125.71 core hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Calculation: &lt;code&gt;32 (CPU cores) * 720 (hours/month) * 103 (hibernation hours/week) / 168 (hours/week)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar calculations apply to memory savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, there are no potential savings, as all nodes are reserved and setting the node count to zero does not release any of them. To achieve savings, some reserved nodes should be converted to on-demand nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: When adjusting node types, consider the cost differences between reserved and on-demand nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scenario-2-autoscaling-node-group-with-on-demand-nodes&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: Autoscaling Node Group with On-Demand Nodes&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#scenario-2-autoscaling-node-group-with-on-demand-nodes&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;NodeGroup: as-cpu-ng(np151adb107448039712d3a24f0d50a)  Total Nodes: 12  Autoscaling: true
  OnDemandNodes: 6  cpu: 192 cores, memory: 384 gib
    Node: cn-beijing.171.18.106.158(i-bp6f7txtyecxuauzgk6m) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.hfc7.8xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
    Node: cn-beijing.171.18.106.76(i-bp6f7txtyecxuauzgk6o) NoSpot, InstanceType: ecs.hfc7.8xlarge, ChargeType: PrePaid
  ...
  Max Potential Saving: CPU: 98880 core hours; Memory: 197760 gib hours
  Potential Saving: CPU: 84754.29 core hours; Memory: 169508.57 gib hours
  Recommendation: no recommendation
  Sum of Deployment Resource Requests: CPU 224.00 cores, Memory 448.00 gibs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this autoscaling node group, maximum potential CPU savings are calculated as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maximum CPU savings: &lt;strong&gt;98,880 core hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Calculation: &lt;code&gt;224 (total CPU cores) * 720 (hours/month) * 103 (hibernation hours/week) / 168 (hours/week)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the potential CPU savings amount to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential CPU savings: &lt;strong&gt;84,754.29 core hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Calculation: &lt;code&gt;192 (active CPU cores) * 720 (hours/month) * 103 (hibernation hours/week) / 168 (hours/week)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential CPU savings are lower than the maximum savings, as the current configuration does not fully optimize node utilization. Adjusting reserved nodes to on-demand could help achieve maximum savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges--solutions&#34;&gt;Challenges &amp;amp; Solutions&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#challenges--solutions&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;workload-state-preservation-and-restoration&#34;&gt;Workload State Preservation and Restoration&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#workload-state-preservation-and-restoration&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cluster Hibernation involves suspending and restoring workloads, and users often worry about incomplete restoration leading to workload unavailability. Since Cluster Hibernation mainly operates by adjusting node groups (releasing and restoring nodes), any issue arising during hibernation will likely affect production as well. In cloud-native environments, applications should be resilient. The best approach is to identify and address the root cause of workload unavailability to ensure the application can withstand node failures. This improves both production stability and resilience during hibernation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintaining-workload-availability-during-hibernation&#34;&gt;Maintaining Workload Availability During Hibernation&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#maintaining-workload-availability-during-hibernation&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep workloads running during hibernation, the following conditions must be met:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The workload should be schedulable on an autoscaling node group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The workload should include the label &lt;code&gt;wiseinf.com/reserved&lt;/code&gt; with a value of &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;. The system will skip workloads with this label during hibernation adjustments. Currently, only three workload types are supported: &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;DaemonSet&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;CronJob&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cluster Hibernation is an effective cost management strategy, especially for non-production environments. The Hibernation Savings Estimation Tool enables users to quickly evaluate potential resource savings for each node pool when applying hibernation strategies. By reviewing common scenarios (autoscaling and non-autoscaling node groups), users can better assess their cost-saving opportunities and adjust settings to reduce resource costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-cluster-optimizer-platform&#34;&gt;About the &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; Platform&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#about-the-cluster-optimizer-platform&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; platform, developed by &lt;strong&gt;WiseInf&lt;/strong&gt;, is a comprehensive cloud-native optimization solution designed to help organizations reduce costs and enhance operational efficiency. By analyzing cloud resources, application performance, user behavior, and cloud vendor data, it identifies cost-saving opportunities and delivers tailored recommendations. The platform also automates the optimization process, minimizing manual errors and streamlining operations to ensure greater efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer v1.3.1 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/09/10/cluster-optimizer-v1.3.1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/09/10/cluster-optimizer-v1.3.1-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.3.1 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spot Node Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides support for Spot instances on both the node and GPU node pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access Key Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Manages access keys for users. With an access key, users can programmatically interact with the &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Hibernation Savings Estimation Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Tools to estimate cost savings from cluster hibernation, with support for both &lt;strong&gt;Amazon AWS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, please refer to: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer v1.3.0 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/07/10/cluster-optimizer-v1.3.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/07/10/cluster-optimizer-v1.3.0-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.3.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Actions&lt;/strong&gt;: Supports resizing of persistent volumes (&lt;code&gt;PV&lt;/code&gt;s), currently limited to &lt;code&gt;Deployment&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Hibernation&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduces the cluster hibernation feature, allowing manual or scheduled hibernation of clusters to free up node resources, with the ability to restore both the cluster and its workload states upon waking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, please refer to: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer v1.2.1 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/05/30/cluster-optimizer-v1.2.1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/05/30/cluster-optimizer-v1.2.1-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.2.1 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database Schema is automatically upgraded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support testing notification channel connectivity to facilitate verification of the correctness of input parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer v1.2.0 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/05/20/cluster-optimizer-v1.2.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/05/20/cluster-optimizer-v1.2.0-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.2.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication and authorization: Supports user authentication and permissions, providing users with two roles: &lt;strong&gt;Administrator&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;User&lt;/strong&gt;. Administrators have all operation permissions, and users only have viewing permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster access account: Supports management of user&amp;rsquo;s cluster access account, and can set a cluster-level cluster access account for each user, including the user&amp;rsquo;s cloud service provider account, and the cluster&amp;rsquo;s Kubeconfig and other configurations. Users can operate the corresponding cluster through this identity. At the same time, if the cluster supports automatic Kubeconfig update, the user&amp;rsquo;s cluster access account can also be updated regularly when in use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated actions: Support application-level resource recommendation, unset resource quotas and memory overflows, and delete unused persistent volumes and other automated actions. Support standard workloads &lt;em&gt;Deployment&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;StatefulSet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;DaemonSet&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;CronJob&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; is not supported, and its resource quota (Resource Quota) cannot be modified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Task management: Supports daily task management operations such as creating, running, re-running, canceling, viewing task logs, and deleting tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer v1.1.0 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/09/cluster-optimizer-v1.1.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/09/cluster-optimizer-v1.1.0-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.1.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Cloud EKS integration: Supports importing AWS EKS clusters and viewing optimization suggestions for the clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPU node: Supports viewing GPU nodes with low GPU utilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick resource association: Supports quick association of resources with corresponding departments, groups, and users through resource tags, and can be displayed on the Web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email notification: For specific optimization strategies, users can subscribe to email notifications to learn about corresponding optimization suggestions through email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster status: Can display the status of Kubernetes and Metrics services imported into the cluster. For abnormal conditions, the cause of the abnormality can be quickly discovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support automatic creation of database Schema: You can use the parameter &lt;code&gt;createDatabaseIfNotExist&lt;/code&gt;=&lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; in the database connection configuration item to indicate whether to automatically create the database if the database does not exist. When the specified user name and password have permission to create a database, the system will automatically create the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly deploy and try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;, see: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer: A cloud-native cluster optimization platform</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/01/cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/01/cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;urgent-need-for-cloud-native-cost-optimization&#34;&gt;Urgent Need for Cloud-Native Cost Optimization&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#urgent-need-for-cloud-native-cost-optimization&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud-native technology is rapidly becoming a cornerstone of modern digital transformation. Gartner predicts that by 2025, more than 95% of new digital workloads will be deployed on cloud-native platforms. The adoption of cloud-native approaches promises more efficient resource utilization, faster application delivery, and enhanced scalability and reliability for enterprises. However, the reality is that many organizations struggle with escalating costs due to various factors. The &amp;ldquo;2021 CNCF FinOps Kubernetes Report&amp;rdquo; found that after migrating to Kubernetes, 68% of enterprises reported an increase in computing costs, with 36% experiencing cost surges exceeding 20%. Moreover, the CNCF&amp;rsquo;s 2023 &amp;ldquo;Cloud Native and Kubernetes Finops Microsurvey&amp;rdquo; highlighted that 49% of respondents witnessed either slight or significant cost increases. Flexera&amp;rsquo;s 2024 State of the Cloud Report also underscored that 59% of users are increasingly concerned about cost optimization. Similarly, the 2023 China FinOps Industry Development Research Report by the FinOps Industry Promotion Alliance revealed that over half of enterprises experience IT resource waste, and more than 80% have a pressing need for IT resource and cost optimization. These statistics underscore the urgent need for effective monitoring, management, and optimization of cloud-native application costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cost Optimization Challenges&#34; src=&#34;//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/01/cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform/suprise.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-challenges-in-cloud-native-cost-optimization&#34;&gt;Key Challenges in Cloud-Native Cost Optimization&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#key-challenges-in-cloud-native-cost-optimization&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idle Resources&lt;/strong&gt;: This issue arises when resources remain allocated but unused, such as application instances in development or testing environments or associated resources like elastic IPs that are not released promptly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misconfiguration&lt;/strong&gt;: Misconfiguration occurs when resources are over-provisioned or scaling mechanisms are improperly configured. Examples include over-requesting CPU or memory to ensure peak performance or incorrectly setting the timing for auto-scaling, leading to oversized application replicas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Automated Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: The absence of automated optimization mechanisms often necessitates manual intervention, complicating operations. For instance, while a disk may experience fluctuating usage, without automation, the system cannot automatically resize the disk to match actual demand, potentially leading to resource wastage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introducing-cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform&#34;&gt;Introducing Cluster Optimizer: A Cloud-Native Cluster Optimization Platform&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#introducing-cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cluster Optimizer is designed to help enterprises reduce cloud costs through an automated and intelligent platform. It addresses the challenges of cost management and optimization in cloud-native architectures by leveraging advanced algorithms, including deep learning and sequential decision-making. Cluster Optimizer analyzes cloud resources, applications, user behavior, and cloud provider data to identify optimization opportunities, such as idle resources and misconfigurations. It offers multi-dimensional optimization recommendations and supports automation to help users reduce costs, improve performance, and enhance operational efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;comprehensive-optimization-recommendations-by-cluster-optimizer&#34;&gt;Comprehensive Optimization Recommendations by Cluster Optimizer:&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#comprehensive-optimization-recommendations-by-cluster-optimizer&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides strategies for node group configuration, including recommended instance types, auto-scaling settings, and optimal minimum and maximum node counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node&lt;/strong&gt;: Evaluates node utilization to recommend appropriate instance types for underutilized nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPU Node&lt;/strong&gt;: Identifies low GPU utilization and suggests suitable instance types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disk&lt;/strong&gt;: Assesses disk utilization and recommends appropriate disk capacities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistent Volume&lt;/strong&gt;: Identifies unused or low-utilization persistent volumes and helps users delete or resize them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;: Offers resource recommendations, alerts for workloads without resource quotas, and monitors out-of-memory (OOM) events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-node-group-recommendation&#34;&gt;Example: Node Group Recommendation&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#example-node-group-recommendation&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, a cluster&amp;rsquo;s nodes are divided into several node groups, each serving a specific purpose (e.g., separating different business units). Cloud providers offer auto-scaling features for these node groups. However, configuring the instance type and setting the appropriate minimum and maximum node values for auto-scaling can be challenging. Cluster Optimizer&amp;rsquo;s node group recommendation strategy suggests the most cost-effective instance type, whether to enable auto-scaling, and optimal minimum and maximum node values based on current load metrics, cloud provider pricing, and geographical considerations. This strategy allows for continuous optimization as the node group&amp;rsquo;s load changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the example below, the node group &lt;code&gt;us-pre-eks-cluster-node-r5a-20240229&lt;/code&gt; currently uses the &lt;code&gt;r6a.4xlarge&lt;/code&gt; instance type, with auto-scaling enabled and both the minimum and maximum number of nodes set to 2. The optimization settings recommend several instance types, including &lt;code&gt;r5a.large&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;r6a.large&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;r5a.2xlarge&lt;/code&gt;. The recommended maximum node count is 7, and the minimum is 1. By applying these optimization settings, the node group&amp;rsquo;s configuration can be adjusted, significantly reducing costs during periods of low utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Node Group Optimization&#34; src=&#34;//localhost:1313/blog/2024/04/01/cluster-optimizer-a-cloud-native-cluster-optimization-platform/nodegroup.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-install-and-try-cluster-optimizer&#34;&gt;How to Install and Try &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;td-heading-self-link&#34; href=&#34;#how-to-install-and-try-cluster-optimizer&#34; aria-label=&#34;Heading self-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We offer a community version of &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; for free installation and trial. For more details, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/docs/setup/&#34;&gt;Free Trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues during installation or trial, please contact us, and we will respond promptly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:business@wiseinf.com?Subject=Try%20Cluster%20Optimizer&#34;&gt;business@wiseinf.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Cluster Optimizer version 1.1.0 Released</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/01/08/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2024/01/08/cluster-optimizer-version-1.1.0-released/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Cluster optimization platform &lt;strong&gt;Cluster Optimizer&lt;/strong&gt; v1.0.0 has been released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alibaba Cloud ACK integration: Supports importing Alibaba Cloud ACK clusters and viewing optimization suggestions for the cluster, including node groups, nodes, disks, persistent volumes, and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings: support create, edit and delete clusters and cloud provider&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
